Guide to the Oregonian photographs collection circa 1850-1984
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Oregonian photographs collection
circa 1850-1984
1884-1984
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Org. Lot 1359
Oregonian (Firm)
60.8 cubic feet 141 document cases, 19 flat boxes, and 13 oversize folders
Photographs used by the Portland newspaper, the Oregonian.
The Oregonian was founded as a weekly paper in 1850 by William W. Chapman, Stephen Coffin, and Thomas Jefferson Dryer. Despite his first name, Dryer was a Whig, and later a Republican; these leanings would have a lasting effect on the paper's editorial stance.
In 1860, Dryer left Portland to campaign on behalf of Abraham Lincoln, leaving the English-born Henry L. Pittock in charge of the paper. The following year, Pittock began publishing the Oregonian as a daily newspaper. In 1865, Pittock hired Harvey W. Scott to be editor of the paper. Scott remained editor until his death in 1910, with the exception of the years 1872-1877, when W. Lair Hill was editor. Notable editors and publishers of the Oregonian since Pittock and Scott have included Palmer Hoyt, Ronald G. Callvert, Ben Hur Lampman, Michael J. Frey, Robert Notson, J. Richard Nokes, and Fred Stickel.
In the 1930s, the paper, struggling financially, hired Stars and Stripes founder Colonel Guy T. Viskiniskki, who dramatically changed the layout and format of the paper as a means of modernizing it. Publishing mogul Samuel I. Newhouse purchased the Oregonian in 1950, ending local ownership. In 1982, when the Oregonian's main rival, the Oregon Journal, went out of business, the Journal's staff and production, which had shared offices with the Oregonian since 1961, were absorbed into the Oregonian.
As of 2016, the Oregonian was the oldest continuously published newspaper in the Pacific Northwest.
The collection contains images from the Oregonian's files, which were acquired through multiple donations from the 1970s to the 1990s. The vast majority of the images are black-and-white production prints.
In addition to photographs taken by Oregonian staff members such as Frank Sterrett, Carl C. Vermilya, Jim Vincent, Peter G. Corvallis, Chuck von Wald, Wes Guderian, and Michael Lloyd, there are photographs from other newspapers and from newswire services such as AP and UPI. The collection also contains a few conceptual drawings, architectural drawings, and maps.
The collection contains photographs of a number of prominent Portlanders and Oregonians, including University of Oregon vice president Dr. Burt Brown Barker, cartoonist Homer Davenport, Portland police chief Leon V. Jenkins, Oregon writers Stewart Holbrook and Ben Hur Lampman, Portland mayor Dorothy McCullough Lee, and Oregon governors Earl Snell and Paul Patterson. Some national and international figures such as presidents Calvin Coolidge and Herbet Hoover, Supreme Court justice Charles Evans Hughes, and Queen Marie of Romania are also represented in the collection. Many photographs of locations, businesses and organizations in Oregon and in Portland are included, as well as photographs of Washington State and of other national and international locations. Subjects covered include agriculture, art, aviation, boats, automobiles, health and medicine, plants and animals, the military, and sports and recreation.
Newspaper production images with extensive markings, often with a caption and date stamp; condition varies.
The collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series A: People
Series B: Oregon
Series C: Portland
Series D: Washington State
Series E: Other US Locations
Series F: Non-US Locations
Series G: Photoseries
Series H: Subjects
Series I: Oversize A
Series J: Oversize B
Series K: Oversize
Series L: Written Materials
Series M: Negatives
The collection is open to the public.
The Oregonian transferred the materials in this collection to the Oregon Historical Society over a number of years; this transfer was incomplete.
Lib. Acc. 18878, 20610, 21908, 22175, possibly Lib. Acc. 20529, 16140, and possibly others.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Barker, Burt Brown, 1873-1969 - Photographs; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933 - Photographs; Davenport, Homer, 1867-1912 - Photographs; Holbrook, Stewart H., 1893-1964 - Photographs; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964 - Photographs; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948 - Photographs; Jenkins, Leon Victor, 1879-1950 - Photographs; Lampman, Ben Hur, 1886-1954 - Photographs; Lee, Dorothy McCullough, 1901-1981 - Photographs; Marie, Queen, consort of Ferdinand I, King of Romania, 1875-1938 - Photographs; Patterson, Paul L. (Paul Linton), 1900-1956 - Photographs; Snell, Earl, 1895-1947 - Photographs; Corvallis, Peter G.; Guderian, Wes; Lloyd, Michael; Sterrett, Frank, 1895-1974; Vermilya, Carl C.; Vincent, Jim; von Wald, Chuck
Oregonian (Firm) - Photographs; Associated Press - Photographers; United Press International - Photographers
Portland (Or.) - Newspapers - Photographs; Portland (Or.) - Photographs; Oregon - Photographs
Newspapers - Oregon - Portland - Photographs; Business enterprises - Oregon - Portland - Photographs; Agriculture - Photographs; Art - Photographs; Aviation - Photographs; Boats and boating - Photographs; Animals - Photographs; Plants - Photographs; Health - Photographs; Military - Photographs; Recreation - Photographs; Sports - Photographs
Oregon; Portland; Photographs
Black-and-white photographs; Photographic prints; Photographs
- People, circa 1875-1984; circa 1915-1984; Series A
  - A (Except Anderson Quintuplets) (1) (Box-folder 1/1)
  - A (Except Anderson Quintuplets) (2) (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Anderson Quintuplets, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/3)
    Photographs of Karen and Eric Anderson's children Audrey, Diane, Owen, Roger, and Scott.
  - Ba (Except Dr. Burt Brown Barker) (1) (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Ba (Except Dr. Burt Brown Barker) (2) (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Barker, Dr. Burt Brown and Wife (Box-folder 1/6)
    One-time vice president of the University of Oregon.
  - Be-Bi (1) (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Be-Bi (2) (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Be-Bi (3) (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Bl-Bo (1) (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Bl-Bo (2) (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Bl-Bo (3) (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Br (Except Dr. J. Whitcomb Brougher) (1) (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Br (Except Dr. J. Whitcomb Brougher) (2) (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Br (Except Dr. J. Whitcomb Brougher) (3) (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Br (Except Dr. J. Whitcomb Brougher) (4) (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Brougher, Dr. J. Whitcomb and Sons (Box-folder 2/5)
    Baptist preacher.
  - Bu-By (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Ca (1) (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Ca (2) (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Ch-Ci (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Cl (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Co (Except Mary Betty Cook and Calvin Coolidge) (1) (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Co (Except Mary Betty Cook and Calvin Coolidge) (2) (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Co (Except Mary Betty Cook and Calvin Coolidge) (3) (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Cook, Mary Betty (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Coolidge, President Calvin and Family (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Cr (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Cu (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Da (Except Homer Davenport) (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Davenport, Home (Box-folder 3/8)
    Political cartoonist. Includes some of his cartoons.
  - De (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Di (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Do (1) (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Do (2) (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Dr-Dy (Box-folder 3/13)
  - E (1) (Box-folder 3/14)
  - E (2) (Box-folder 4/1)
  - E (3) (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Fa-Fl (1) (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Fa-Fl (2) (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Fo-Fu (1) (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Fo-Fu (2) (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Ga-Ge (1) (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Ga-Ge (2) (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Gh-Gi (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Gl-Go (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Gr-Gw (1) (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Gr-Guw (2) (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Ha (Except Willard Prescott Hawley Family) (1) (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Ha (Except Willard Prescott Hawley Family) (2) (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Ha (Except Willard Prescott Hawley Family) (3) (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Hawley, Willard Prescott, Sr. Family (Box-folder 5/4)
    Includes Willard P. Hawley, Sr. and wife, Willard P. Hawley, Jr. and wife, and Willard P. Hawley III.
  - He-Hi (1) (Box-folder 5/5)
  - He-Hi (2) (Box-folder 5/6)
  - He-Hi (3) (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Herman, Jim ("Tiny") and Family (Box-folder 5/8)
    Heavyweight boxer from Astoria born Oscar Koch
  - Ho-Hy (Except Stewart Holbrook, Herbert Hoover, and Charles Evans Hughes) (1) (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Ho-Hy (Except Stewart Holbrook, Herbert Hoover, and Charles Evans Hughes) (2) (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Ho-Hy (Except Stewart Holbrook, Herbert Hoover, and Charles Evans Hughes) (3) (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Ho-Hy (Except Stewart Holbrook, Herbert Hoover, and Charles Evans Hughes) (4) (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Holbrook, Stewart and Family (Box-folder 6/1)
    Portland author.
  - Hoover, President Herbert (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans (Box-folder 6/3)
  - I (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Ja-Je (Except Leon V. Jenkins) (1) (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Ja-Je (Except Leon V. Jenkins) (2) (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Jenkins, Leon V. and Wife (Box-folder 6/7)
    Chief of Portland Police 1919-1933 and 1946-1948.
  - Jo-Ju (1) (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Jo-Ju (2) (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Ka-Ke (Except Mildred Keats) (1) (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Ka-Ke (Except Mildred Keats) (2) (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Keats, Mildred Louise (Box-folder 6/12)
    1920s actress who married Albert Bradshaw in 1932.
  - Ki-Ky (1) (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Ki-Ky (2) (Box-folder 6/14)
  - La (Except Ben Hur Lampman) (1) (Box-folder 7/1)
  - La (Except Ben Hur Lampman (2) (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Lampman, Ben Hur (Box-folder 7/3)
    Longtime Oregonian editor and Poet Laureate of Oregon.
  - Le-Li (Except Harriet Leach and Dorothy McCoullough Lee (1) (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Le-Li (Except Harriet Leach and Dorothy McCoullough Lee (2) (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Leach, Harriet (Box-folder 7/6)
    Soprano singer in the 1920s.
  - Lee, Mayor Dorothy McCullough (Box-folder 7/7)
    Mayor of Portland 1949-1953.
  - Lo-Ly (1) (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Lo-Ly (2) (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Ma (Except Queen Marie of Romania) (1) (Box-folder 7/10)
    Does not include names beginning with Mc or Mac.
  - Ma (Except Queen Marie of Romania) (2) (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Queen Marie of Romania (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Mc/Mac (1) (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Mc/Mac (2) (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Mc/Mac (3) (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Me-Mi (Except Ezra Meeker) (1) (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Me-Mi (Except Ezra Meeker) (2) (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Meeker, Ezra (Box-folder 8/6)
    Pioneer and traveler.
  - Mo-My (Except Tom Murray) (1) (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Mo-My (Except Tom Murray) (2) (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Murray, Tom (Box-folder 8/9)
    A bandit who killed a guard and escaped the Oregon State Penitentiary in 1925. Includes photographs related to Murray's murder trial.
    See also: Oregon - Salem - Prison Escape.
  - N (1) (Box-folder 8/10)
  - N (2) (Box-folder 8/11)
  - O (1) (Box-folder 8/12)
  - O (2) (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Pa-Pe (Except Gov. Paul Patterson) (1) (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Pa-Pe (Except Gov. Paul Patterson) (2) (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Pa-Pe (Except Gov. Paul Patterson) (3) (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Patterson, Gov. Paul and Wife (1) (Box-folder 9/5)
    Governor of Oregon 1952-1956, who died in office.
  - Patterson, Gov. Paul and Wife (2) (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Patterson, Gov. Paul and Wife (3) (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Ph-Pl (Except Elise Bristol Platt) (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Platt, Elise Bristol (Box-folder 9/9)
    1928 Rose Festival Queen.
  - Po-Pu (1) (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Po-Pu (2) (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Q (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Ra-Ri (1) (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Ra-Ri (2) (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Ra-Ri (3) (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Ra-Ri (4) (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Ro-Ry (1) (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Ro-Ry (2) (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Sa (1) (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Sa (2) (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Sa (3) (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Sc (Except Bertha Mae Schwan) (1) (Box-folder 10/10)
  - Sc (Except Bertha Mae Schwan) (2) (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Schwan, Bertha Mae (Box-folder 10/12)
    Portland-born singer.
  - Se-Sh (Except Glenn Shelley) (1) (Box-folder 10/13)
  - Se-Sh (Except Glenn Shelley) (2) (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Se-Sh (Except Glenn Shelley) (3) (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Shelley, Glenn (Box-folder 11/3)
    Keyboard player.
  - Si-Sl (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Sm-Sp (Except Gov. Earl Snell) (1) (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Sm-Sp (Except Gov. Earl Snell) (2) (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Snell, Gov. Earl (Box-folder 11/7)
    Governor of Oregon 1943-1947, who was killed in a plane crash while in office.
  - St-Sz (1) (Box-folder 11/8)
  - St-Sz (2) (Box-folder 11/9)
  - St-Sz (3) (Box-folder 11/10)
  - St-Sz (4) (Box-folder 11/11)
  - T (1) (Box-folder 11/12)
  - T (2) (Box-folder 11/13)
  - T (3) (Box-folder 12/1)
  - U (Box-folder 12/2)
  - V (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Wa (1) (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Wa (2) (Box-folder 12/5)
  - We-Wei (1) (Box-folder 12/6)
  - We-Wi (2) (Box-folder 12/7)
  - We-Wi (3) (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Wo-Wy (Except Wolfenson Family) (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Wolfenson Family, 1976 June (Box-folder 12/10)
    Traveling family that was lived in a converted schoolbus
  - Y (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Z (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Business and Civic Groups (Box-folder 12/13)
    Group portraits taken from "Groups - Business" and other folders depicting at least one Oregonian but not referring to a single organization or company. Also includes two photographs showing multiple 19th century Portland mayors.
  - Oregonian Employees (Box-folder 12/14)
    See also: Portland - Oregonian 75th Anniversary Celebration.
  - Newspaper Columnists, circa 1972 (Box-folder 12/15)
    Photographs of columnists from various newspapers whose columns were printed in the Oregonian.
    Includes transparencies.
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 12/16)
- Oregon, circa 1900-1984; Series B
  - 4-H Club (1) (Box-folder 13/1)
  - 4-H Club (2) (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Abert Lake and Rim (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Abiqua Falls (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Adair Air Force Base (Box-folder 13/5)
    Also called Camp Adair. Located near Corvallis, the US Government decomissioned the base in 1969. The site later became a community known as Adair Village.
    Includes a 1977 photograph related to Chicano-Indian Study Center of Oregon, located in Adair Village.
  - Agate Beach (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Albany (Box-folder 13/7)
  - Albany Timber Carnival (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Alder Creek (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Alkali Lake (Box-folder 13/10)
  - Aloha (Box-folder 13/11)
  - Alsea River (Box-folder 13/12)
  - American Legion (Box-folder 13/13)
  - American Pioneer Trails Association (Box-folder 13/14)
  - Amity (Box-folder 13/15)
  - Antelope (Box-folder 13/16)
  - Anthony Lakes (Box-folder 13/17)
  - Applegate (Box-folder 13/18)
  - Arch Cape (Box-folder 13/19)
  - Arch Rock (Box-folder 13/20)
  - Arlington (Box-folder 13/21)
  - Arrah Wanna Camp (Box-folder 13/22)
  - Ashland (Box-folder 13/23)
  - Mt. Ashland (Box-folder 13/24)
  - Ashland Creek (Box-folder 13/25)
  - Astoria (1) (Box-folder 13/26)
  - Astoria (2) (Box-folder 13/27)
  - Aumsville (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Aurora (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Mt. Bachelor (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Bagby Hot Springs (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Baker (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Baker County (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Bandon (Box-folder 14/7)
  - Banks (Box-folder 14/8)
  - Barlow Home (Box-folder 14/9)
    Residence of William and Sam Barlow, located between Canby and Aurora.
  - Barlow Trail (Box-folder 14/10)
  - Battle Rock State Park (Box-folder 14/11)
  - Bay City (Box-folder 14/12)
  - Bayocean (Box-folder 14/13)
  - "Beach Scenes" (Box-folder 14/14)
    Consists of images found in folder labeled "Beach Scenes" whose locations were not specified. Original folder had subheadings reading, "Bathing Beauties Contests," "Seaside," "Nye Beach," and "Newport." Might also contain images that were taken at Rockaway or elsewhere on the Oregon coast.
  - Bear Valley (Box-folder 14/15)
  - Beaver Boys' State (Box-folder 14/16)
  - Beavercreek (Box-folder 14/17)
  - Beaverton (1) (Box-folder 14/18)
  - Beaverton (2) (Box-folder 14/19)
  - Bend (Box-folder 14/20)
  - Benson State Park Work Project (Box-folder 14/21)
  - Berlin (Box-folder 14/22)
  - Bethel Collge (Box-folder 14/23)
    School in Polk County which later merged with Monmouth University (now Western Oregon University).
  - Bethel Gas Turbine Plant (Box-folder 14/24)
  - Big Sky Ranch (Box-folder 14/25)
  - Big Sturgeon Lake (Box-folder 14/26)
  - Black Butte (Box-folder 14/27)
  - Blue Lake (Cascades) (Box-folder 14/28)
  - Blue Lake (Unknown Location) (Box-folder 14/29)
  - Blue Lake Regional Park (Box-folder 14/30)
  - Blue River (Box-folder 14/31)
  - Boardman (Box-folder 14/32)
  - Boardman - Hearing on Boeing Deal, 1969 November 29 (Box-folder 14/33)
    Debate on whether the Oregon Legislature should approve of a land deal to Boeing Corp. for land at Boardman. Hearing actually took place in Heppner.
  - Boiler Bay State Park (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Bombs and Bombings (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Bonneville (Box-folder 15/3)
    Includes 1934 photograph of Mrs. E. Bell Hill's house near site of Bonneville Dam.
    See also: Oregon - Dams - Bonneville.
  - Boring (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Boulder Creek Wilderness (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Boys & Girls Aid Society (Box-folder 15/6)
    Includes a photograph of Tom McCall in costume for a Boys & Girls Aid Society event.
  - Boy Scouts (Box-folder 15/7)
  - Breitenbush (Box-folder 15/8)
  - Breitenstein Mill, 1975 (Box-folder 15/9)
    Series of photographs of abandoned mill north of Sublimity.
  - Bridges, Subseries 1
    - Abernathy Creek (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Alsea Bay (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Astoria (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Barton Bridge (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Boone Bridge (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Bridge of the Gods (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Briggs Rapids Bridge (Box-folder 15/16)
    - Coos Bay (Box-folder 15/17)
    - Covered (Box-folder 15/18)
    - Crooked River Bridge (Box-folder 15/19)
    - Dillard (Box-folder 15/20)
    - Eugene (Box-folder 15/21)
    - Feagle Creek Bridge (Box-folder 15/22)
    - Finn Rock Bridge (Box-folder 15/23)
      Located on the McKenzie River.
    - Fullquartz Landing (Box-folder 15/24)
      Consists of photograph of old pilings at the site of the bridge.
    - Hood River (Box-folder 15/25)
    - John Day River (Box-folder 15/26)
    - Lewis & Clark Bridge (Box-folder 15/27)
    - Longview-Rainier Bridge (Box-folder 15/28)
    - Myrtle Point (Box-folder 15/29)
    - Ocean Beach Highway (Box-folder 15/30)
    - Oregon City-West Linn Bridge (Box-folder 15/31)
      Part of I-205.
    - Patterson Bridge (Box-folder 15/32)
      Located on the Rogue River.
    - Pudding River Bridge (Box-folder 15/33)
    - Rhododendron (Box-folder 15/34)
    - Skipanon River (Box-folder 15/35)
    - Snake River (Box-folder 15/36)
    - Suislaw River Bridge (Box-folder 15/37)
    - The Dalles Bridge (Box-folder 15/38)
    - Thomas Creek Bridge (Box-folder 15/39)
    - Three River Bridge (Box-folder 15/40)
    - Tualitin River (Box-folder 15/41)
    - Umatilla Bridge (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Umpqua River (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Union Pacific Railroad Bridge (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Wilson River (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Wilsonville (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Yaquina Bay Bridge (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Unnamed/Unspecified (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Broken Top Mountain (Box-folder 16/8)
  - Brookings (Box-folder 16/9)
  - Brooks (Box-folder 16/10)
  - Brothers (Box-folder 16/11)
  - Brown's Island (Box-folder 16/12)
  - Brownsmead (Box-folder 16/13)
  - Brudos Murder Case (Box-folder 16/14)
  - Bryce Coleman Home (Box-folder 16/15)
    Residence near Aloha that included furniture made from repurposed materials.
  - Brownsville (Box-folder 16/16)
  - Bull Run Watershed (Box-folder 16/17)
    Includes some images of the Bull Run Dam.
  - Bullard's Beach State Park (Box-folder 16/18)
  - Bureau of Land Management (Box-folder 16/19)
  - Burns (Box-folder 16/20)
  - Burns Bros. Truck Stop (Box-folder 16/21)
    Located south of Portland
  - Burnt River (Box-folder 16/22)
  - Butteville (Box-folder 16/23)
  - Camassia Nature Preserve (Box-folder 16/24)
  - Camp Abbott (Box-folder 16/25)
  - Camp Arago (Box-folder 16/26)
  - Camp Arrowhead (Box-folder 16/27)
  - Camp Benson (Box-folder 16/28)
  - Camp Butte (Box-folder 16/29)
  - Camp Christmas Seal (Box-folder 16/30)
  - Camp Clark (Box-folder 16/31)
  - Camp Clatsop (Box-folder 16/32)
  - Camp Collins (Box-folder 16/33)
  - Camp Colton (Box-folder 16/34)
  - Camp Easter Seal (Box-folder 16/35)
  - Camp Enterprise (Box-folder 16/36)
  - Camp Fire Girls (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Camp Hancock (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Camp Ma-Ku-Ala (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Camp Meehan (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Camp Menucha (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Camp Meriweather (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Camp Namanu (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Camp Pendleton (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Camp Rilea (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Camp Rivendale (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Camp Sherman (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Camp Tamarack (Box-folder 17/12)
  - Camp Westwind (Box-folder 17/13)
  - Camp White (Box-folder 17/14)
  - Camp Wilkerson (Box-folder 17/15)
  - Camp Withycombe (Box-folder 17/16)
  - Canby (Box-folder 17/17)
  - Canby - Clackamas County Fair (Box-folder 17/18)
  - Cannon Beach (Box-folder 17/19)
    Includes a photograph of an unidentified road "near Cannon Beach."
  - Canyon City (Box-folder 17/20)
  - Canyon View Camp (Box-folder 17/21)
  - Canyonville (Box-folder 17/22)
  - Cape Arago State Park (Box-folder 17/23)
  - Cape Blanco (Box-folder 17/24)
  - Cape Kiwanda (Box-folder 17/25)
  - Cape Lookout State Park (Box-folder 17/26)
  - Cape Mears (Box-folder 17/27)
  - Cape Perpetua (Box-folder 17/28)
  - Cape Sebastian State Park (Box-folder 17/29)
  - Caples House (Box-folder 17/30)
    Located in Columbia City.
  - Carlton (Box-folder 17/31)
  - Carver (Box-folder 17/32)
  - Cascade Head (Box-folder 17/33)
  - Cascade Lakes (Box-folder 17/34)
  - Cascade Locks (Box-folder 17/35)
  - Cascade Mountains (Box-folder 17/36)
  - Cascade Ski Club (Box-folder 17/37)
  - Cascadia State Park (Box-folder 17/38)
  - Catholic Centennial, 1946 July (Box-folder 18/1)
    Unclear if photograph within was taken in St. Paul or elsewhere in Oregon.
  - Cave-Ins (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Cave Junction (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Cazadero Tunnel (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Cedar Creek (Box-folder 18/5)
  - Cedar Fir Park (Box-folder 18/6)
  - Cedar Hills (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Cedar Mill (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Celilo Canal (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Celilo Falls (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Celilo Village (Box-folder 18/11)
  - Central Oregon (Box-folder 18/12)
  - Central Point (Box-folder 18/13)
  - Champoeg (Box-folder 18/14)
  - Chanticleer Point (Box-folder 18/15)
  - Chapel of the Hills (Box-folder 18/16)
    Located on Mt. Hood Loop Highway.
  - Cheney Dance School (Box-folder 18/17)
    Dance instruction held near Mt. Hood
  - Cherry Grove (Box-folder 18/18)
  - Children's Homes (Box-folder 18/19)
    Photographs related to children's homes in unspecified locations in Oregon.
  - Chiloquin (Box-folder 18/20)
  - Chinook Pass (Box-folder 18/21)
  - Christmas Celebrations (Box-folder 18/22)
  - Christmas Lake Basin (Box-folder 18/23)
  - Christmas Valley (Box-folder 18/24)
  - Civil Air Partol (Box-folder 18/25)
  - Civil Defense (Box-folder 18/26)
  - Clackamas (Box-folder 18/27)
  - Clackamas County (Box-folder 18/28)
  - Clackamas County Center (Box-folder 18/29)
  - Clackamas County Sheriff's Office (Box-folder 18/30)
  - Clackamas Industrial Area (Box-folder 18/31)
  - Clackamas River (Box-folder 18/32)
  - Clackamas Town Center (Box-folder 18/33)
  - Clarno State Park (Box-folder 18/34)
  - Clatskanie (Box-folder 18/35)
  - Clatsop County (Box-folder 18/36)
  - Clatsop Plains Church (Box-folder 18/37)
  - Clear Lake (Box-folder 18/38)
  - Cleawox Lake (Box-folder 18/39)